Support Admin Watch on
kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
I have no time for this!
Get out!
Father, have mercy...
I can't bear
to lose this child
in my womb, Father.
You will have
that child aborted.
And you will marry
Gobernadorcillo Flores!
Father!
Father, I beg you!
I'm ready to marry Leandro.
They didn't mean
for it to happen,
so just let them be!
Father ordered to have
Mr. Raul killed.
I'll take you away, Carmelita.
Will you really not stop
with this nonsense?!
Eduardo!
Farewell to you,
Juanito Alfonso.
It's all my fault.
If not for me, Juanito
would still be alive.
I'm to blame...
If only I hadn’t fallen
in love with Juanito.
It's my fault.
Everything's my fault.
Get out!
I don't want it!
I'm not hungry!
I said get out!
It's me, Carmela.
Mother Olivia?
Mother...
How did you get in here?
The guards are strict, aren't they?
Doña Soledad helped me get in.
Don't worry.
Carmela, dear.
I was suddenly awoken last night.
I know something bad happened.
Juanito is dead.
I'm sorry.
Mother Olivia?
I can feel it...
Juanito is still alive.
What?
Where is the diary?
Here.
The moment this diary burst into flames
and turns to ash...
That would be the sign
that you failed your mission.
To save Juanito.
Every page of this diary,
contains your story with Juanito.
His brush with death...
Caused these burns.
In these pages of the diary.
Is it because the diary is still intact?
Does that mean Juanito's still alive?
Juanito is still alive?
I want to tell him I love him.
Mother Olivia.
No matter where he is, I
want to tell him I love him.
But Carmela...
You must remember.
If you fail your mission...
You won't be able to
return to your own time.
Your father sent Maria to Laguna.
And you're still here because
your wedding to Leandro
is set by the end of the month.
How about Josefina?
She's also locked in her room.
Your father discovered
she also helped Mr. Raul escape.
My dear...
I just want to know.
Why did you plan to elope with Juanito?
But before,
you were adamant not to get married to him.
I can feel you're also in love.
Even though you won't admit it.
It's such a shame that all these happened.
So much pain and conflict.
There...
There are things.
Things that cannot stay with us.
Let Juanito go.
You're just gonna make
things hard for each other.
He's just gonna suffer more.
Because your father will not
allow you to end up with him.
My daughter.
I know that only someone who loves truly
can do this sacrifice.
You should rest.
W-what are you doing here?
I need to return to my room.
There's bad news.
Theresita is here in
San Alfonso with Sonya.
What?
She wants to plead for Ignacio's case.
Wait. We have to stop her.
If the officials see her,
her life will be in danger.
I'm sorry but they didn't
know that Miss Sonya escaped.
Please let my husband go.
I swear we won't cause any more trouble.
We won't show our faces here.
Ignacio is all that's left of their family.
Anything.
I'll do anything just let him go, please.
There is only one way
for you to be with your husband.
And that is death.
Don't you people have hearts?
You're laughing while
another person is suffering?
Carmelita!
Please excuse my daughter's action.
Don Alejandro,
as the second-in-command
here in San Alfonso,
what is your judgment?
Just put her in prison.
Let us wait for the
Gobernadorcillo's return.
Sonya!
Carmelita...
If something happens to me...
Please tell my brothers I
apologize for leaving them behind.
And tell Ignacio,
that my love for him
will stay forever true.
What would people say?
That you gave consideration
to the people you know?
It's not gonna help us
if we execute a pregnant woman in public.
That is why I instructed General Seleno
to give whatever her punishment is.
In secret!
Sonya!
Wait, I need to see Sonya!
What did you do to her?!
Sonya!
- Sonya!
- I told you not to insist.
Just stay there!
Sonya!
Sonya?
Wait... wait...
Wait!
Sonya?
Sonya!
Sonya.
I'm sure Sonya is happy
and at peace in the afterlife.
Far from the suffering she
experienced in this world.
We will be praying at the plaza later.
May I borrow the rosary that
Aunt Rosario gave you before?
I want to use it as I
lead the prayer later.
Wait a moment.
Is this the one?
Here.
Thank you.
Don't take it back, okay?
Ever since Sonya died,
I haven't talked to Don Alejandro.
I just chose to keep quiet and ignore him.
Carmelita, dear.
Do you remember the story
of your Father's ancestors?
Don Patricio Montecarlos
was a pure Spanish settler from Spain.
He lived here in 1684.
He married a farmer's daughter.
Felicidad.
He bought so many land here.
And established lots of businesses.
Rice, wheat,
and several animal farms.
That is why the Montecarlos clan was known
as the richest in San
Alfonso for centuries.
What would Don Patricio
and Doña Felicidad feel
if they knew their descendant
turned out to be a horrible person?
Come on, let's head to the plaza.
- Josefina might be waiting for us.
- Don Alejandro! Don Alejandro!
The rebels attacked the plaza!
Miss Josefina was stabbed.
She's in critical condition.
- What? What happened to my daughter?!
- Who's responsible for this?!
What happened to...
He was the one who attacked your daughter.
Animal! You shameless wretch!
Degenerate!
Don Alejandro! That's enough!
We need this rebel alive!
So that we can catch the others.
Answer me!
Who's the mastermind behind all of this?
Are you from Catapang's rebel group?
I said speak!
Or would you prefer to have this bullet
bored into your brain?
What?!
Remove his shirt!
Now,
answer our questions!
What is the purpose of this attack?
Where is your base?
Catapang is our leader.
But...
The mastermind behind all this..
Who also planned
the murder of Josefina.
Was Juanito Alfonso.
The son
of the late Gobernadorcillo.
After Juanito learned
what happened to Sonya...
He came up with the plan.
In order to bring justice
for our families.
Whom you murdered and tortured!
Don Alejandro!
Heneral Seleno!
The rebels also attacked the prison.
They broke out Ignacio and Eduardo.
I knew it!
The attack at the plaza
was a diversion
so that you can raid the prison!
Look at what you've done, Carmelita!
You helped this scum escape!
You gave them the
chance to hurt your sister!
The stab wound in her abdomen is deep.
Her liver was badly injured.
She also lost a lot of blood.
She needs to stay here for
her medication and recovery.
Fight.
Don't leave us.
You're here with me?
Don't you worry.
I promise.
I will not leave you.
That's a promise, okay?
I will not forget it.
The doctor said Josefina's
condition is getting better.
Maybe she can be discharged
the day after tomorrow.
Good thing Josefina's
condition is better now.
I am more at ease now.
Because nothing bad happened to you.
I wouldn't be able to forgive myself...
If something like that happened to you.
Go on and eat.
I cooked some Caldereta.
I am sure
that what my beloved made is delicious.
If this is what
awaits me at the dinner table
every day and every night...
I bet I wouldn't leave the house anymore.
Come on, Carmelita.
Eat with me.
I don't have any appetite.
Do you know?
Every time I'm going through something...
And when I'm mourning the
deaths of my fellow soldiers...
I always think.
What if this is my last day?
That's also how I think every time I eat.
Even though the food's not to my taste.
I still try to eat.
Because what if
that breakfast, lunch, or dinner...
Would be my last meal.
I believe
that we have to give importance to food.
And to the chances
that we have something to eat.
We are not assured...
When would be our last.
Alright.
Mm!
It's too salty!
He doesn't think it's salty?
Ah... Leandro?
There's other food in the kitchen.
Do you want me to get it?
I will finish all of this.
My beloved worked hard to cook it.
I'm glad that
I was able to make you smile.
Give me your glass.
I'll pour you some water.
Thank you.
Here. You need this.
Is the coffee to your liking?
It's delicious. Very good, Don Alejandro.
Tell the cook to wrap two more fishes.
I'll take it home.
No problem.
We have lots of fishes here.
Here comes the photographer!
Don Alejandro,
it's ready now.
When did you marry...
Judge Velario?
Isn't he too old for you?
He was chosen by those close to me
so that no matter what happens...
I wouldn't get hurt anymore.
Carmelita.
Do I look alright now?
Of course.
You know, the rosary I
gave you really suits you.
Thank you.
This rosary carries your love.
Very well.
Is everyone ready?
I'm sure you look beautiful in our picture.
Mother...
Josefina?
Josefina!
- Josefina?!
- Josefina!
What's happening to you?!
Judge Velario, please call a doctor!
Of course. Right away.
- Josefina?
- Call for help!
Get a doctor here!
Please help us!
Josefina?
Josefina!
Please help us!
Get a damn doctor here now!
Josefina, my dear!
Wake up, child.
Dear...
Josefina!
- No!
- Josefina!
- Josefina! Josefina!
- My child!
Josefina!
- Josefina!
No, my child! Josefina!
Father, excuse me.
Child.
If...
there's one person that is to blame
for Josefina's death...
It's me.
This is all my fault, Carmelita.
I conspired with Gobernadorcillo Flores.
to take revenge for
Don Mariano’s belittling...
and his desecration of our family.
When he called off your wedding to Juanito.
I was blinded by rage.
It's true that we tainted his name.
And made up stories...
That ended up taking his life.
We also know Captain
Corpuz is quite powerful.
And also Sergio Alfonso.
That's why they were also targeted.
Josefina's life
was the price I had to pay
for all my sins towards the Alfonsos!
Father!
Father, that's enough.
Even then, I did not stop!
I also took the life of
Sonya who was innocent!
Father...
Now I don't know what to do, Carmelita.
You're my only hope.
Father...
Carmelita...
You need to marry Leandro.
The Montecarlos and Flores
families must become one.
If not,
all I worked hard for will be for nothing.
Our family will lose its protection.
Carmelita...
After everything that has happened,
in the end, it's still my fault.
That's why I should be the one to fix it.
It's me who needs to sacrifice.
How did that happen!?
The rebels attacked
Mr. Rosalejos' home earlier.
And they left something on your door step.
The severed head of Mr. Rosalejos.
From this day on,
I command...
The strict surveillance
of the civil guards...
Within the town of San Alfonso.
Anyone caught with weapons in their house,
and doing suspicious activities,
will be arrested.
Rebels will be executed.
There are times when
you just have to choose
your mind over your heart.
Because if I follow
my feelings for Juanito,
It will only end
badly, for both of us
and for my family.
And the only way to keep everyone safe
is for me to marry Leandro.
Mother Olivia,
isn't it unfair for Carmelita
to wake up one day
and find that she's married to Leandro?
What Carmelita would
remember once she wakes up...
will be the time before she met Juanito.
But it will only happen
if you succeed in your mission.
Carmelita!
You need to go somewhere safe.
Let's go!
Judge Valenciano!
You sentenced my father to
death without enough evidence!
Don't!
That will be the basis of your fate!
Die!
You must escape! Quickly!
Leandro!
You!
You were the one who murdered
my helpless wife and child!
And you!
On your knees!
I'm your friend!
I'm an ally!
Ignacio, don't!
I never knew you could betray
my father and Don Mariano!
And you let my wife and child die!
Don't... Please...
Ignacio, don't!
Ignacio!
Hold on!
Carmelita, dear.
Thank God, you're alive.
How are you feeling?
It was a good thing that
the bullet only scraped you.
Doctor Hidalgo said
your hearing might not
return to normal.
You might get dizzy
or hear buzzing in your ear.
How's Maria?
My beloved Mother,
I hope you can forgive me for my decision.
Don't worry because I know
Eduardo will take care of me,
and our child.
I ask for your forgiveness.
With love, Maria.
I am worried for the state of our family.
There are rumors that it was Maria
who gave rebels information.
So that they can attack
during your wedding to Leandro.
And Juanito?
He's imprisoned at Fort Santiago.
They’re forcing him to reveal
where the rebels are hiding.
Mother...
May I see and talk to Juanito?
I know what I'm asking
is impossible, but...
But I won't be at peace
if I don't see him at least.
Your request is quite difficult, child.
But I will find a way.
I will do everything for you.
Thank you very much.
Miss?
Have some water.
Thank you.
Esmeralda.
Thank you for helping me.
I also would like to apologize
for what Josefina and I did
when we let Raul escape.
I am truly sorry.
It is I who needs to apologize, Miss.
Because of me, Mr. Juanito almost died.
And Mr. Ignacio and Eduardo as well.
Carmelita, my dear.
I am grateful and happy.
That you are here by my side.
Always remember, my child.
I will forever be thankful
that the Lord blessed me with you.
And I believe,
no matter the challenge may come your way,
you will always find a
way to get through it.
Even though Carmelita and I are different,
I learned to love the
people she cares about.
Especially Doña Soledad.
Because of her, I get to have a mom again.
The one you're waiting for has arrived.
Alright.
Use the backdoor.
Take him to Carmelita's room.
Mother,
who is your guest?
What are you doing here?
He's here to confess.
Something about Juanito.
I will give you
one last chance, Juanito.
Tell me where the rebel base is!
You may go home, Carmelita.
Mother Olivia took the fall.
Because of that...
She was sentenced to death.
Do not worry about me, Carmela.
I have been alive for so long.
Before God even created humans.
- The guards' camp is over there!
- I will not leave you, Juanito!
- Please escape, Carmelita!
- I won't leave you!
Thank God I found you.
You must get out of here, Miss.
Don't let Mr. Leandro find you.
Why?